一份诺玛早餐.
特制的.
One of Norma's breakfasts.
Made special.
上帝保佑诺玛.
God bless Norma.
先放着吧. 先放着吧, 谢了.
Maybe later. Maybe later, thanks.
局里的事务怎样?
How's things at the station?
厄尔的棋局
是最伤脑筋的.
Earle's chess game
is the big concern.
那个人毫无松懈
的意思.
The man has a poor sense
of recreation.
是啊.
Yeah.
我们正挺着呢, 暂时还行.
We're holding up, for now.
嘿, 你和库珀能处理好的.
这个镇单纯的很.
Hey, you and Cooper can handle it.
lt's a pretty simple town.
以前是.
Used to be.
我想世界正
赶着我们前进呢.
l guess the world's
just caught up to us.
安妮.
Annie.
- 嗨.
- Hi.
雪莉, 这是我妹妹, 安妮.
Shelly, this is my sister, Annie.
嗨, 安妮. 欢迎.
诺玛和我讲过你所有的事.
Hi, Annie. Welcome.
Norma's told me all about you.
- 我所有的事?
- 雪莉就像自家人一样.
- All about me?
- Shelly's like family.
我们的家, 没有一个
像样的.
With our family, that's not exactly
a character reference.
你和妈妈相处的如何?
How did you and Mom get along?
嗯, 我们可以谈谈她,
又或者谈点别的，能让我们高兴的事.
Well, we can talk about her,
or we can feel good about things.
我选后者.
l vote for plan B.
我也是. 我很高兴你来这.
Me too. l'm glad you're here.
感觉有点奇怪. 现实世界.
Feels a little strange. The real world.
一些琐事, 比如我差点忘了
怎么用钱.
Little things, like l'd almost forgotten
how to use money.
最近我们修道院里
用的都是代币.
Closest we get in the convent
was bingo chips.
不用优待我, 诺玛. 你保证.
No charity, Norma. Promise.
别担心,
我会让你工作到倒下为止.
Don't worry,
l'm gonna work you till you drop.
引人注目.
Compelling.
哈里快崩溃了.
Harry's about to hit bottom.
他吃东西吗?
ls he eating?
你觉得他什么时候
会回来工作?
When do you think
he'll come back to work?
我想我们很快就会知道的.
l guess we'll find out soon.
需要帮忙吗?
Need a hand?
这个问题
应该由我来问你.
That's a question
l should be asking you.
你才是高级督察, 库珀.
You're the senior lawman, Cooper.
我们还是
各安其位吧.
Let's just let the rain fall
as it has been.
再说, 我讨厌文书工作.
Besides, l hate paperwork.
这儿比调查局那边还乱,
全都是些国际档案.
This is worse than the Bureau,
with all its international documentation.
埃卡, 乔西...
Eckhardt, Josie...
这是她的验尸报告.
This is the autopsy on her.
海沃德医生说
他无法确定死因.
Doc Hayward said
he couldn't determine cause of death.
尸体只有65磅.
The body only weighed 65 pounds.
- 那怎么可能?
- 我不知道.
- How is that possible?
- l don't know.
或许和她死去时
我在房间里所见的有关.
Maybe something to do with
what l saw in the room when she died.
或许在我们路过坟墓是
最好要吹着口哨.
Maybe we'd better just whistle
on our way past the graveyard.
- 就是.
- 厄尔那边呢?
- Yeah.
- Anything on Earle?
踪迹全消.
还在等他回应呢.
Trail's stone-cold.
Still waiting for his response.
- 鞋.
- 是拖鞋.
- Slip.
- Slippers.
你知道吗, 里欧,
一个人是不懂欣赏
You know, Leo,
you can't really appreciate
乡村生活有多么的滋补
除非你真正身在其中生活.
how tonic country life is
until you're actually right here, living it.
- 烟斗?
- 好极了.
- Pipe?
- Splendid.
即便你之前
去过乡村,
Even if you've been
to the country before,
当你试图去想像时
却像回到过去,
when you try to imagine
what it would be like to go back,
影像是残缺不全的.
the image is imperfect.
脑袋的影像
总是不完美的.
The mental image
is always imperfect.
我说的对吧?
Am l right?
心照不宣是可以接受的, 里欧.
Tacit agreement is acceptable, Leo.
你此时无声胜有声.
Your silence speaks volumes.
又或者说, 至少是一段
偶然未加标点的文章段落.
Or if not volumes, at least the
occasional unpunctuated paragraph.
好, 让我们来看看可怜的库珀
这次是怎么走出这一步棋.
Well, let's see what move our poor
Cooper's come up with this time.
这不是一步棋.
This isn't a move.
这是个把戏.
This is a trick.
他让这游戏陷入了僵局.
He's playing a stalemate game.
库珀根本不知道
有僵局这一招!
Cooper doesn't know
the meaning of stalemate!
有人在帮他.
He's getting help.
我不能容忍别人
不按规矩玩游戏.
l cannot tolerate people
who do not play by the rules.
那些不安本分的人!
People who shirk the standards!
很多人会因此而后悔的.
Many people are going to regret this.
会了吗?
Got it?
女士们, 容许我说,
Ladies, may l say,
你们俩将如此愉悦的代表着
you'll both delightfully represent
神圣的大自然.
the sanctity of nature.
来根烟?
Cigarette?
我宁愿让肺保持干净.
l prefer to keep my chest clear.
伟大的神, 真健康.
The great god, fitness.
- 你和品寇谈过了吗?
- 品寇是什么东西?
- Have you spoken with Pinkle?
- What's a Pinkle?
他是来为松鼬
演讲的.
He's giving a talk
on the pine-weasel.
- 濒临绝种动物.
- 哦, 有意思.
- The endangered animal.
- Oh, lovely.
是什么来的? 是浣熊吗? 还是别的?
What is it? A raccoon or something?
是一种鼬.
A ferret.
欧蕊?
Audrey?
噢, 好极了.
你们俩该协力合作.
Oh, great.
You two should coordinate.
你想的美.
You are dreaming.
你好.
Hello.
看来你
很卖力啊.
Looks like you're trying
to run lumber upstream.
有什么可以帮你吗, 维乐先生?
How can l help you, Mr. Wheeler?
荷恩. 嗯, 就是我们
那天晚餐时说的.
Horne. Well, the talk
that we had at dinner.
- 我不能--
- 很抱歉我当时的无礼, 你也觉得吧?
- l can't--
- l'm sorry l was rude, wasn't l?
只是每当提到我家里,
我就会有点激动.
Just that when it comes to my family,
l get a little excitable.
- 是我的错，我又不是谁，却在这儿到处指手划脚的
- 我们需要帮助, 人尽皆知,
- Who am l to waltz in out of nowhere?
- We need help, anyone can see that,
而且我想不出有谁
比你更胜任这工作了.
and l can't think of anyone
better qualified for the job than you.
喂?
Hello?
我们到底在讲什么?
What are we talking about anyway?
我在道歉
同时你也道歉.
l was apologizing
and you were apologizing.
我们俩都有不是了.
你想出去走走吗?
We're both real sorry about something.
You wanna go out somewhere?
不合时宜, 对吧? 不太好?
Bad time, right? lt's not good?
噢, 不, 不, 很合时宜.
Oh, no, no, it's great.
去野餐怎样?
How about a picnic?
我们需要些户外用品.
篮子, 地毯...
We need outdoors stuff.
A basket, blanket...
食物.
Food.
我不会煮东西.
l don't know how to cook.
我敢打赌
有人帮你在厨房里做呢.
l'll bet you someone
in the kitchen does.
这是让人们知道
松鼬到底长什么样子.
This is just to show people
what the pine-weasel looks like.
我完全能理解这个概念,
饼扣先生.
l understand the concept perfectly,
Mr. Dinkle.
是品扣. 我名字叫品扣.
Pinkle. The name is Pinkle.
但我先讲清楚
用一个动物标本
But what l'm trying to make clear
is that using a stuffed animal
去象征濒临绝种的动物
作为一个生态倡议书
to represent an endangered species
as an ecological protest
构建极端不和谐啊.
constitutes the supreme incongruity.
嗯, 说的是, 基巴.
Well, that's clear, Dick.
哈里?
Harry?
嘿, 库.
Hey, Coop.
我们在国际刑警组织那儿
拿到了乔西的档案.
We got Josie's dossier
in from lnterpol.
没兴趣.
Not interested.
另外，杀死埃卡,
还有试图谋杀我
ln addition to killing Eckhardt,
trying to kill me
- 和在西雅图杀死乔纳森,
- 都结案了.
- and killing Jonathan in Seattle,
- Closed cases.
她还因多宗重案
在香港被通缉.
she's also wanted for a variety
of felonies in Hong Kong.
我不要听这些.
l don't need to hear this.
她还因卖淫
被逮捕过2次, 哈里.
She's also had
two prostitution arrests, Harry.
哈里, 最终这些会帮助你了解
她其实是个不知悔改的惯犯.
Harry, eventually it's gonna help you
to know she was a hardened criminal.
一个杀手.
A killer.
走开.
Get out of here.
我知道现在不易过.
l know it's not easy right now.
走开行不行.
Just get out of here.
滚开! 滚!
Get out of here! Go!
门是开着的.
The door was open.
乡村习俗. 我们都互相信任.
A country habit. We're all so trusting.
我叫琼斯.
My name is Jones.
我是埃卡先生生前的
行政助理.
l was executive assistant
to the late Mr. Eckhardt.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
我是来加紧处理
他尸体运回香港的.
l've come to expedite the transport
of his body back to Hong Kong.
悲剧啊, 发生那些事.
你知道的, 他真的爱乔西.
Tragic, what happened.
You know, he really did love Josie.
难道我们不是吗?
Didn't we all?
他们将被埋葬
在一起.
They're going to be buried
side by side.
那么他们就可以
互相监视了.
So they can keep an eye
on each other.
我想你的挖苦
是有因由的.
l guess you have your reasons
to be bitter.
哦, 尽管把我称作一个健康的无神论者吧.
Oh, just call me a healthy skeptic.
现在, 说你来见我的真正
目的是什么?
Now, why did you really
come to see me?
我来这儿给你捎个礼物.
可以吗?
l came here to give you a gift.
May l?
我可不这么想.
l don't think so.
慢点.
Slowly.
托马斯送的.
From Thomas.
我还有些东西要整理,
然后，我今晚就走.
l have a few things to tidy up,
then l'll be leaving tonight.
祝你走运, 马爹利太太.
Good luck, Mrs. Martell.
打搅了, 我找
比尔或艾琳·海沃德.
Excuse me, l'm looking
for Bill or Eileen Hayward.
哦, 他们现在不在家呢.
能帮你吗?
Well, they're not here right now.
Can l help you?
那好吧, 杰尔·奎格医生,
Well, l'm Dr. Gerald Craig,
是伟在医校的
老朋友.
an old friend of Will's
from medical school.
嗯, 那, 你看,
我去斯波坎市参加会议
And, well, you see,
l have a convention in Spokane
所以我就想顺道拜访
给他们个惊喜.
and so l just thought l'd swing by
and surprise them.
你是哪个女儿?
Which daughter are you?
- 唐娜.
- Donna.
你要进来坐坐吗,
奎格医生?
Would you like to come in,
Dr. Craig?
那就打搅了.
l'd appreciate that.
要给你拿点喝的吗,
奎格医生? 汽水之类的?
Can l get you something to drink,
Dr. Craig? A pop or something?
谢谢你, 不了, 不了.
Thank you, no, no.
这是你们当地的报纸?
ls this your local paper?
是啊. 相当小的镇, 呵?
Yeah. Pretty small town, huh?
这, 在你住进城市之前
可别瞧不起这儿镇小.
Now, don't knock small towns
until you've lived in the city.
唐娜, 知道吗,
Donna, you know,
看来伟已经在这儿
找到他自己一片小小的宁静乐土了.
it seems like Will has found himself
a little piece of heaven here.
好了, 你不还有2个姐妹吗?
Now, don't you have two sisters?
- 是啊, 他们比我小.
- 2个都和你一样漂亮?
- Yeah, they're younger than me.
- Are they both as beautiful as you?
那, 我不知道.
Well, l don't know.
你知道吗, 你爸爸和我,
我们以前常围坐在一起
You know, your dad and l,
we used to sit around
试着去设想
我们未来的生活会怎样.
and try to figure
how our lives would work out.
现在看来，他似乎
比我更接近目标.
And it seems like he's come
a little closer to the mark than l have.
- 你在读高中?
- 是啊，真不幸.
- You're in high school?
- Unfortunately.
我也觉得是.
l felt exactly the same way.
你了解, 高中难熬啊,
是啊.
You know, high school is difficult,
you know.
你不知道
你将来想要干什么,
You have no idea
what you want to do with your life,
似乎你的人生
一片茫然.
so it seems that absolutely none of it
applies to your life.
你说的是.
You're right.
嗯, 别担心. 会好起来的.
Well, don't worry. lt'll all work out.
目前来说, 你就只管去做些荒谬言行
尽情享受所有的怪诞事物好了.
For now, you just enjoy it
in all its absurdity.
好的.
Okay.
噢, 我带了个小礼物给你爸爸.
Oh, l have a small gift for your dad.
那么, 我能相信你不会打开它吗?
Now, can l trust you not to open it?
当然了.
Sure.
你知道吧, 提到学校,
You know, speaking of school,
伟和我就是30年前
的这个月毕业的.
Will and l graduated
30 years ago this month.
所以 我--
一个给他的小纪念品.
So l--
lt's a small remembrance for him.
那好, 我该走了.
Well, l should be on my way.
噢, 这是我住的地方
的电话号码.
Oh, this is the number
where l'm staying.
希望迟点再会, 唐娜.
l hope to see you later, Donna.
我也是.
Me too.
你准备的怎样了, 皮特?
How are you holding up, Pete?
我已经查过历史纪录里的
每一个比赛的僵局了.
l've been through every
stalemate game in recorded history.
我还草草的编了几个
农家风格的僵局
And l've jerry-rigged
a few of these country standoffs
书上没有的.
that they don't write about in books.
不过没用. 我意思是,
这世上根本就没有僵局
But it's no use. l mean,
there isn't a stalemate game on earth
就算你连几个步兵
都没损失.
that you don't lose
at least a few foot soldiers.
我是指, 就连最经典的和斯曼棋局.
l mean, the classic Herbstman.
你也只能救6步棋.
目前, 我能作点改善.
You wind up with six pieces.
Now, l can improve on that.
但就算我在一半时间内走到那儿
救12步,
But even if l get there in half the time
and wind up with 1 2,
那意味着还是有6个人会死.
that means six people die.
你尽力而为吧, 皮特.
Do your best, Pete.
云顿·厄尔有性急的恶习
和他的天才一样是与生俱来的.
Windom Earle's genius carries with it
the vice of impatience.
他不想要兵卒.
他要皇.
He doesn't want pawns.
He wants royalty.
保护那些, 特别是皇后,
那么我们就能挫败他.
Protect those, particularly the queen,
and we can frustrate him.
你不能那样走.
You can't do that.
我的学生们.
My students.
马爹利先生, 安迪还没用放行棋
就走骑士了.
Mr. Martell, Andy moved his knight
without doing the little hook thing.
你不一定非要
用放行棋. 那是随意的.
You don't have to do
the little hook thing. That's optional.
安迪, 走骑士
必须先走放行棋.
Andy, the knight
has to do the little hook thing.
- 每次都要吗?
- 那是一种特权.
- Every time?
- lt's a privilege.
其它没有一个是这样走的.
No one else gets to make that move.
那好吧, 马爹利先生.
Okay, Mr. Martell.
我猜有些人才不会想那么多
他们爱干啥干啥.
l guess some people don't know
quite as much as they think they do.
将军.
Check.
我想我们
最好来见你.
We thought it best
we come see you.
正如你所知, 那个在我后颈
的图案
As you know, that pattern
on the back of my neck
是我遇到那个什么时
出现的...
appeared during my experience
with...
当然,
不知道当时它怎么会在那儿的.
Of course,
no idea as to how it got there.
然后你今天注意到了?
And you noticed it today?
是我的圆木注意到的. 我记得.
My log noticed. l remember.
你记得什么, 玛格利特?
What do you remember, Margaret?
看我的后腿.
Look at the back of my leg.
我那时才7岁.
l was 7 years old.
我当时正走在树林子里,
l went walking up in the woods,
然后当我回来时, 我被告知
原来我已经失踪1天了.
and when l got back, l was told
that l had disappeared for a day.
我能记起的全部就是一道闪光,
All l could recall was a flash of light,
和我腿上的这印记.
and that mark was on my leg.
我们3个都记的那光.
We all three recall the light.
还有, 猫头鹰的叫声.
And also, the call of the owl.
是, 我记得.
Yes, l remember.
还仅有另一次
我又见过那景象和听过那声音
The only other time l saw that sight
and heard that sound
就在我丈夫去世前.
was right before my husband died.
在火里.
ln the fire.
- 我和某些事有着关联.
- 是的.
- l'm connecting with something.
- Yes.
是什么?
What?
我不知道.
l don't know.
噢, 别把我埋葬
Oh, bury me not
在往昔的大草原上
郊狼在那儿哀嚎
On the old prairie
Where the coyotes howl
风呼呼的吹
And the wind blows free
在一个狭窄的墓穴里,
3个旁边躺着6个
ln a narrow grave,
Six-by-3
不要现在埋葬我
Don't bury me now
在孤单的大草原上
On the lone prairie
之前没人对我
唱过歌.
No one's ever sung a song
to me before.
肯定有人对你唱过小夜曲
至少会有一次或两次.
You must have been serenaded
at least once or twice.
我没受到多少歌唱的启发.
l don't inspire much singing.
大多数男孩都害怕.
Most boys are afraid.
那, 只是他们不了解你.
Well, they don't know you then.
真不了解.
Not really.
我不觉得
有任何人了解我.
l don't think
anybody really knows me.
听起来像是个警告.
lt sounds like a warning.
我知道.
l know.
如果有另一个人...
lf there's another guy...
曾经有过一个,
但不复存在了.
There was someone,
but not anymore.
不再有了.
There's nobody.
那, 你现在打算怎么办呢?
So, what do you wanna do now?
知道牛仔的一些小把戏吗?
Know anymore cowboy tricks?
如果你有一个套索
在那个野餐篮子里,
lf you've got a lariat
in that picnic basket,
我能套住路过的家畜.
l could lasso passing cattle.
我想这儿几里内都不会有一头奶牛的.
l don't think there's a cow for miles.
那就套迷路狗, 浣熊,
鸟, 黄鼠狼.
Stray dogs, raccoons,
birds, weasels.
有人来看你.
You had a visitor.
是谁?
Who's that?
一个和你上医校的
叫杰尔·奎格的人.
Somebody you went to medical school
with named Gerald Craig.
杰尔·奎格?
那不可能, 唐娜.
Gerald Craig?
That's not possible, Donna.
嗯, 真的. 他说他去
斯波坎市参加会议.
Well, yeah. He said he was on his way
to a convention in Spokane.
他还知道我的一切.
He knew everything about me.
这是他的号码, 还有这个.
Here's his number, and this.
杰尔·奎格是我的室友.
Gerald Craig was my roommate.
后来他在蛇河
玩漂流艇时淹死了.
He drowned on a rafting trip
on the Snake River.
我当时就在那儿, 唐娜.
我还尝试去救他.
l was there, Donna.
l tried to save him.
哦, 那...
Well, then...
是个公墓.
lt's a cemetery.
骑士对王的主教，三.
Knight to King's Bishop 3.
那个人, 他非常危险.
That man, he's very dangerous.
别再让他进来这儿,
你听懂了吗?
Don't let him in here again,
do you understand?
- 肯定了.
- 我拿这个去给库珀.
- Sure.
- l've got to take this to Cooper.
纳丁, 我在这
要对你说的是...
Nadine, what l'm here
to say to you is...
看着你现在和迈克...
Seeing how you're with Mike now...
看你窘的
好可爱.
lt's so cute the way
you get embarrassed.
既然
我也已经有别人了...
And since
l have found someone else...
纳丁, 我不肯定
你明不明白这事.
Nadine, l'm not sure
you're gonna understand this.
当然, 我明白, 小艾艾.
Of course, l understand, Eddie.
这又不是在耍嘴皮子.
This isn't just a little spat.
纳丁,
Nadine,
你知道
艾德正在提议什么吗?
do you know
what Ed is suggesting?
不太明显.
我们又不是, 就像, 在这儿探讨相对论.
lt's not too obvious.
We're not, like, talking relativity here.
我们在分手呢.
主要来说, 是终结性分手.
We're breaking up.
Major, final breakup.
那好, 是啊, 从学术上来说,
我想这算是一个分手, 但--
Well, yes, technically,
l guess it is a breakup, but--
嗯, 不过还不止
是那样而已t, 纳丁.
Well, it's a little more
than that, Nadine.
艾德, 你好严肃.
Ed, you are so serious.
现在都什么年代了.
These are the dating years.
你表现的好像
发生了什么大事.
You're acting like
this is some really big deal.
医生?
Doc?
艾德, 这枚什么秘诀
或咒语.
Ed, there are no secret tricks
or magic words.
就像是伤口旁的
疤痕组织逐渐消褪.
lt's like the dissolving
of scar tissue around a wound.
当她的脑袋开始感觉安全后
她会再次重新认识现实.
She'll start to see reality again
when her mind begins to feel safe.
那, 将会是什么时候?
Well, when will that be?
难说.
l can't say.
那些组织包块堆积在那儿
相当难搞.
That tissue's packed in there
pretty hard.
好了. 这样, 1件事
我实在不想看到的, 艾德,
Okay. Well, one thing
l really don't wanna see, Ed,
不要因嫉妒而愤怒.
不要迈克因此发生任何意外.
are any incidents with Mike.
No jealous rages.
嗯, 要不只发生一件好了.
Well, maybe just one.
我放弃了.
l give up.
纳丁, 你和艾德
准备要离婚了.
Nadine, you and Ed
are about to get a divorce.
我想我的左眼已经瞎了.
l think l've gone blind in my left eye.
- 雪莉?
- 怎么.
- Shelly?
- Yeah.
你看过这个了?
Have you seen this?
哦, "双峰小姐."
Oh, ''Miss Twin Peaks.''
噢, 你肯定是拿我来开玩笑.
Oh, you've gotta be kidding me.
有一个现金奖
和一个奖学金.
There's a cash prize
and a scholarship.
- 我打赌你肯定能行.
- 我不觉得.
- l bet you could walk away with it.
- l don't think so.
很容易的, 你来段演说,
再问你几个问题...
lt's easy, you give a speech,
you answer a few questions...
双食店小姐, 你会做点什么
为世界带来和平呢?
Miss Double R Diner, what would
you do to bring about world peace?
那, 我会把
全世界的领袖聚在一起,
Well, l would bring
all the world leaders together,
让他们围成一圈
手拉手.
make them form a circle
and join hands.
如果你握着拳头的话
就不能手拉手咯.
Because you can't make a fist
holding hands.
你赢定了.
You're a shoo-in.
我还有一张单要下呢.
l have an order up.
你的汉堡来了.
Here's your burger.
有什么高兴的要跳起舞来?
What's with the dance?
噢, 我老板说我应该去
参加选美. 双峰小姐.
Oh, my boss told me l should
enter a pageant. Miss Twin Peaks.
你可以当它是个玩笑,
但你非常漂亮.
You can kid about it,
but you are very pretty.
我觉得你应该参选.
l think you should enter it.
谢谢, 但我不觉得
我自己有多漂亮.
Thanks, but l don't think
of myself as pretty.
那时主观而已, 你知道的.
lt's an inner thing, you know.
你要喝点什么吗?
Would you like something to drink?
是的, 请给我来一杯
浓黑咖啡.
Yes, l'd like a cup
of deep black joe please.
马上来.
Coming right up.
你一定是诺玛的妹妹.
You must be Norma's sister.
我是安妮.
l'm Annie.
- 你怎么知道?
- 戴尔·库珀. 地方执法机关.
- How did you know?
- Dale Cooper. Local law enforcement.
一定很忙吧.
Must keep you pretty busy.
的确是.
Sure does.
你会在镇上呆一段时间?
Are you staying in town for a while?
我可能会在这呆好长一阵子.
l might be here quite a while.
我也是
lt's happened to me.
看来你挺喜欢这里的.
Looks like it's grown on you.
因为这里有它的魅力所在.
lt has a way of doing that.
我煮的有点浓.
l made it a little strong.
没事.
Okay.
你煮的味道刚刚好, 安妮.
You made it just right, Annie.
我们书屋那边
有麻烦了.
We've got a problem
at the Book House.
库珀探员, 豪克,
警长抓狂了.
Agent Cooper, Hawk,
the sheriff's gone off.
没有钉子固定的家俱
都给他打个稀巴烂.
He's broken every piece
of furniture not nailed down.
我真不知该怎么办才好.
l honestly don't know what to do.
没事的, 安迪.
lt's okay, Andy.
嘿, 戴尔副警长.
Hey, Deputy Dale.
工作如何?
How's business?
好了, 哈里,
现在有一点点复杂了.
Well, Harry,
it's a little complicated at the moment.
那就是法律的好处了,
它没有生命, 你不能杀死它!
That's a good thing about the law,
it doesn't breathe, you can't kill it!
哈里, 我有一个想法.
Harry, l've got an idea.
你为什么不把枪给我呢.
Why don't you hand me that gun.
我不相信在我一生人中
会把我的枪交到任何一个人手中!
l don't believe l've ever handed my gun
over to anybody in my entire life!
这或许
就是个开始的好时机.
This might be
a damn fine time to start.
你知道
我做过的其他事吗?
You know something else
l've never done?
我从没横渡过海洋.
l've never crossed the ocean.
从未去过中国.
Never got to China.
而她来到我身边.
She came to me.
她让所有事都变得美好起来.
And she made everything better.
所有事都是那么美好.
Everything so much better.
哈里.
Harry.
你的生活仍属于你自己的.
乔西并没有带着它一起走.
Your life is still your own.
Josie didn't take that with her.
我本应该带她走.
l should have gotten her away.
我早该
带她离开这里!
l should have
taken her away from here!
我爱她.
l loved her.
她本不该死的.
She didn't have to die.
我不明白.
l don't understand.
有太多事情我不明白.
There's a whole lot l don't understand.
我们都那样.
We're all like that.
今晚找人
看着他.
Have somebody keep an eye
on him tonight.
我从没见过他这样.
l've never seen him like this.
那就像你去
最心爱的地方远足
lt was like taking a hike
to your favorite spot
却发现曾在那儿的湖
已经枯竭成空洞.
and finding a hole
where the lake used to be.
乔西是有能量的.
Josie had power.
爱一个人不容易啊,
付出太多.
A man who doesn't love easily,
loves too much.
- 一个好人.
- 最好的.
- A good man.
- The best.
继续前进.
Keep going.
那是你们定的特别蜜月套房
庆门先生和夫人?
That's a special honeymoon suite
for Mr. and Mrs. Hinkman?
对. 是的.
That's correct. Yes.
我们是从波斯曼州来的.
We're from Bozeman originally.
但我太太觉得
看看郊野景色会不错.
But my wife thought that it would be
nice to see the countryside.
还有, 你知道吗, 你们双峰镇这儿
的乡村非常漂亮.
And, you know, you have some
very pretty country here in Twin Peaks.
- 你会在我们这久住吗?
- 就怕不够久.
- Will you be with us long?
- Not long enough.
不, 住到明天就可以了,
因为我们准备出深海钓鱼.
No, just until tomorrow if that's okay,
because we're going deep sea fishing.
噢, 太好了.
Oh, goody.
好, 那我们现在
准备上房去了, 我和--
Okay, so we'll just be
going on up now, me and--
- 我和庆门太太.
- 噢, 是迈克吗?
- Me and Mrs. Hinkman.
- Oh, is that Mike?
苏珊, 你好吗?
Susan, how are you?
好.
Fine.
学校见.
l'll see you at school.
请上房吧.
The room please.
行李我们会自己拿的.
l think we can handle the bags.
首先,
First of all,
我想感谢你们在座的各位来
出席这个不可思议的盛会.
l would like to thank all of you
for this marvelous turnout.
很高兴看到
那么多人
lt's very gratifying to see
so many people
真切的
关心身处的环境.
who are sincere
about their environment.
『停止格斯伍』作战计划
对那些企图
The Stop Ghostwood campaign
is a determined effort
把我们美丽的西南森林
变成畸怪大型游乐场
to keep the rabid development
interests from trying to turn
相关的急剧发展
起到决定性的影响.
our beautiful Northwest forests
into a monstrous amusement park.
毁坏几个世纪以来
未被骚扰过的动物保护区.
Destroying animal preserves which
have been undisturbed for centuries.
那个小小的世界
是几种濒临灭绝动物
The little worlds
that serve as sanctums
的栖息圣地.
for several endangered species.
不仅仅是
小松鼬.
Not the least of which
is the little pine-weasel.
好了，在这结束之前,
Before moving along,
我想再次提醒大家
生态学不是一种奢侈科学.
l would just like to remind all of us
that ecology is not a luxury science.
它也不是一场
取悦大家的秀.
lt is not about
pleasant appearances.
而是关乎生存.
lt is about survival.
关乎我们是否做好
长期进行下去的准备.
About whether we are all
going to make it, period.
但千万不要低估了
视觉享受的价值,
But not to understate the value
of visual pleasure,
我们马上来到时装表演环节.
we come to the fashion show.
现在, 如果你们当中任何人觉得
有些模特很眼熟,
Now, if any of you think you recognize
some of the models,
那是因为他们
就是来自本地社区的居民,
it's because they are concerned
members of the community,
今晚慷慨仁慈的贡献出
他们宝贵的时间.
who have graciously given
of their time tonight.
那好, 女士们，先生们,
闲话少说, 这是我们的主持人,
So, ladies and gentlemen,
to kick things off, here is our host,
理查·揣眉.
Richard Tremayne.
谢谢你. 济济一堂啊.
Thank you. Splendid gathering.
我们的小露西
正穿这一套令人愉悦的
Our little Lucy
is wearing a delightful
合成针织保暖装, 既有北方的舒适感
又有南方的潇洒自如.
mix of warm, northern comfort
and southern insouciance.
一件优雅的精纺羊绒外套
外加一条彩格披肩,
An elegant worsted wool jacket
over a plethora of plaid,
再以波尔卡小圆点衬衫作点缀.
with a hint of polka dot.
实在无与伦比, 是吧?
在一个漆黑的无月之夜, 穿上修身短裙
lt's fabulous, isn't it?
A moonless night, black, slim skirt
那身打扮就似乎在向世界说,
"嘿, 我在这儿呢."
with a look that always says,
''Hey, world, l'm here.''
布伦南先生现在身上正穿着的是
一件消防车风格的红色高领毛衣
Mr. Brennan is wearing
a fire engine red turtleneck
在全羊毛彩格披肩衬托下的是
潘多腾衬衫.
beneath an all-wool plaid
Pendleton shirt.
水牛纹短马靴令他更显
红黑相间的整体感.
He completes this look with his red
and black, buffalo-checked jodhpurs.
犹如一份宣言
为男人保留着
For the man who wants
to make a statement
想要的随意感,
无论他是在外工作的征途中,
while retaining that casual feel,
whether he's out mastering a task,
还是乘着仆仆风尘
去赴会.
or riding the breeze
of a chance meeting.
可以了, 安迪.
That's it, Andy.
照这样下去, 我们都要迟了.
所以，等下我们出去那
At this rate, we're running late.
So if we could all sort
动作要快点
全都快快跟着理查.
of hurry Richard along
with some quick movement out there.
我穿这着这东西好热.
l'm hot in this thing.
你热? 我还穿的像只绵羊呢.
这全都是精纺厚绒呢.
You're hot? l'm dressed like a sheep.
All this worsted.
然后我想揣眉先生
And l think Mr. Tremayne
看到这些女孩子
会更热呢.
is getting more than a little hot
with all these girls.
- 我们的下一位模特是...
- 去, 去, 去.
- Our next model...
- Go, go, go.
好啊, 这不就是环保领袖约翰·缪尔吗?
红杉树之友啊.
Well, if it isn't John Muir,
friend of the redwoods.
凯萨琳, 你来真好.
Catherine, how good of you to come.
本, 亲爱的,
你这忽悠的都什么人啊?
Ben, darling,
who are you kidding with all this?
我绝对是百分之一百的诚心诚意.
l am absolutely 1 00 percent sincere.
噢, 少来了吧.
看你在跟谁说话.
Oh, come on.
Look who you're talking to.
我们都一条道上的.
We're in the same line of work.
你一向都
有点显而易见的, 除了这次.
You've always been
a little more obvious, but this.
凯萨琳, 在你的一生里,
曾有过,
Catherine, have you ever,
in your entire life,
真正改变你的
体验吗?
had an experience
that truly changed you?
拜托了, 省着点吧，想重新兜揽生意的话
就老实对我说好了.
Please, spare me the born-again
sales pitch and level with me.
你别指望阻挡
我的发展大计,
You can't hope to stop
my development plans,
说, 你到底期望
在这事上能获得些什么?
so, what do you actually expect
to gain from all this?
第一次荡涤
A first scrubbing
那一颗整个西北
最肮脏的良心.
on one of the dirtiest consciences
in the entire Northwest.
而且我满怀希望, 它也会在你身上发生的.
And hopefully, it will happen to you.
凯萨琳,
Catherine,
我知道你格斯伍的
计划是什么.
l know what your plans
for Ghostwood are.
就算我以前看待人生的方式
的确和你一样.
And granted l used to see life
exactly the way you do.
而且不管我做了多少生意
赚了多少钱,
And no matter how many deals
l made or how much money l made,
在内里, 我仍是一个漆黑,
悲哀，泥头泥脸的土佬而已.
inside, l was still a black,
miserable clod of dirt.
而我现在寻找的是一件
在生命真正让你快乐的事,
l am finding that the one thing
that really affords you joy in life,
唯一靠得住的事, 就是施与.
the only authentic thing, is giving.
不要等到你临死的那一天
才发现这个真理.
Don't wait until you're on
your deathbed to find that out.
上帝保佑你!.
God help you.
给你说的好像是那么回事儿.
You actually sound like you mean it.
我真的. 为了你, 为了我, 未来.
l do. For you, for me, the future.
凯萨琳,
为什么你不借这个机会
Catherine,
why don't you take this opportunity
去超越你的自大狂
和一生的自私自利,
to transcend a lifetime
of megalomania and egocentricity,
然后给我们写张巨额支票
作为停止格斯伍计划的活动经费.
and write us a big fat check
to help stop Ghostwood.
那现在, 为你们介绍的是
一只濒临绝种的小生物,
And now, to introduce you
to an endangered little critter,
它的家园
最近正遭受着
whose home
is presently under attack
被提上议程的格斯伍发展计划
的无情糟蹋, 有请提姆·品寇先生.
by the proposed Ghostwood
development project, Mr. Tim Pinkle.
谢谢你, 基巴.
谢谢你, 谢谢你.
Thank you, Dick.
Thank you, thank you.
好, 嗨, 一切都还好吧?
Well, hi, how's everything going?
那好.
That's good.
女士们，先生们,
我带来了一个小伙伴
Ladies and gentlemen,
l have with me a little fellow
它不知道
危险在等着他.
who doesn't understand
the peril that awaits him.
一个天真无知在一个发疯似的世界里.
An innocent in a world gone mad.
一个发疯似的世界.
A world gone mad.
不再囉嗦了,
女士们，先生们,
Without further ado,
ladies and gentlemen,
我向你们呈现
濒临绝种的松鼬.
l give you
the endangered pine-weasel.
现在看到的这个是
鼬鼠家族的其中一个品种.
Now, this species
is of the weasel family.
他不单止对我们人类
没有任何侵犯性，而且还有美丽的皮毛,
And not only is he non-aggressive
to us humans and has beautiful fur,
并且, 他天生就是
啮齿类中控制能力的佼佼者.
but also, he is by nature
an excellent controller of rodents.
不幸的是, 这友善的小家伙
有难以置信的好奇心
Unfortunately, this little friendly fellow
is incredibly curious
这让他很容易
中圈套.
making him very easy
for one to trap.
他还会被明亮发光的物体
所吸引.
He is also attracted to bright
shiny objects.
- 一定是给我的胸章吸引了.
- 对啊.
- Must be my studs.
- Yeah.
还有一样令人吃惊的,
信不信由你
lt also is amazing,
he is particularly attracted
他还特别容易被多种气味所吸引,
尤其那种非常廉价的古龙水.
to various smells like, believe it or not,
very cheap cologne.
噢, 这是干什么?
Oh, what's this?
我想它要
给你一个吻, 基巴.
l think it wants
to give you a kiss, Dick.
- 噢, 别了, 品寇先生.
- 来嘛. 来嘛.
- Oh, please, Mr. Pinkle.
- Come on. Come on.
- 好啦, 给他一个吻嘛.
- 一个吻?
- lt's all right, give him a kiss.
- A kiss?
好样的. 来一个.
Attaboy. Come on.
你好, 看这儿, 小香客--
Hello, there, little pilgrim--
噢, 不, 不, 不.
Oh, no, no, no.
大家别慌张. 别慌张.
他是完全无害的.
Nobody panic. Don't panic.
He's completely harmless.
他已经快濒临绝种了.
He's already endangered.
别慌张, 各位,
请别慌张.
Don't panic, anybody,
just don't panic.
- 大家别慌张.
- 请各位, 冷静.
- Nobody panic.
- Please everyone, calm down.
留在你的座位.
Stay in your seat.
- 你还好吧?
- 我还好.
- You all right?
- l'm fine.
一只开溜鼬鼠引发的骚动.
Lot of fuss over a loose weasel.
- 或许我们该帮忙.
- 我不知道.
- Maybe we should help.
- l don't know.
有点小刺激
对这帮人可能是好事.
A little excitement
might do this crowd some good.
- 你来看时装表演吗?
- 不, 我来看你.
- Did you come for the fashion show?
- No, l came for you.